rackspace.co.uk 2011-01-18

# UK Privacy Policy

UK Privacy Policy
V: 100118
Rackspace respects your privacy. The purpose of our Privacy Policy is to demonstrate our firm commitment
to the privacy and protection of all persons who provide personal data to Rackspace. This Privacy Policy
describes the ways we collect information from and about you, and what we do with the information, so
that you may decide whether or not to provide personal information to us.
By visiting Rackspace® websites or are otherwise providing your personal information to Rackspace via
any other means, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Policy.
For purposes of this policy, the term “visitor” includes visitors to our website who are not yet customers,
those who become customers, as well as those who do not become customers; whether you upload
information to our website, download it, or are merely visiting our website. You can choose not to provide
certain information when using our website but then you might not be able to take advantage of many of
its features.
1. WHAT DO WE COLLECT AND WHERE?
The personal information we collect may include: your name, contact information, financial information
and payment card details, IP addresses, Live Chat Messages, Telephone conversations, product and service
selections and orders or other things that identify you individually.
Generally, we may collect personal information in the following manners:
         you may provide your personal information to us via chat, email or other written correspondence,
         telephone calls, web based forms, or other means;
         we use automated technical means to collect personal information about our website visitors for
         example by use of cookies; and
         via third party providers.
Web Visit
You may visit our Website in any of the following ways:
         By using your browser to navigate to www.rackspace.co.uk;
         By viewing an advertisement displayed on a third party website that is served content by our web
         server;
         By viewing an email that is served content by our web server;
When you visit our website, our server logs your IP address (unique network addresses), the time and
duration of your visit, and the time and duration of the pages on our website you view. If you arrive at our
website by clicking a paid advertisement (including a paid search engine result) or a link in an email, then
we will capture information that tracks your visit from that link. If you arrive at our website by clicking a
non-paid source, such as link in a non-paid search engine result or an unsponsored link on another website,
we may capture information that tracks your visit from that source, to the extent we are able to do so. We
                                                                                                 Rackspace Ltd
                                                                    4 The Square, Stockley Park, Uxbridge UB11 1ET
                                                            Tel: +44 (0) 20 8734 2500 Fax: +44 (0) 20 8606 6107
                                                                                         Web: www.rackspace.co.uk

UK Privacy Policy
V: 100118
may also capture information about your computer system, such as your browser type and operating
system.
We will likely place a cookie on your hard drive during the web visit. A cookie is a unique alphanumeric
identifier that we use to help us identify the number of unique visitors to our website, whether or not those
visitors are repeat visitors, and the source of the visits. Cookies cannot be executed as code or used to
deliver a virus. Other servers cannot read them and personal information cannot be gathered from them.
They are simply an identifier shared between you and us to allow us to improve the services we offer to
you through our Website. If you do not wish cookies to be placed on your computer, then they can be
disabled in your web browser. The option to do so is normally found in your browser's "security settings"
section. However, please note, permanently disabling cookies in your browser may hinder your use of our
Website as well as other websites and interactive services.
A web beacon, also known as a web bug, is a small graphic (usually 1 pixel x 1 pixel), that is embedded in a
web advertisement, email, or page on our web site, but is invisible to you. When you view a page on our
web site, an email or an advertisement your web browser will request the web beacon from a web server,
which in turn will set a cookie in your web browser containing a unique identifier. This unique identifier
will be linked to log information that is used to track your movements on our web site in order to
determine the effectiveness of content and advertising campaigns.
We do not collect personal information about you as part of a web visit, but web visit information may be
tied to other information (including personal information) we collect from you via chat, web forms, and the
other means we describe in this Privacy Policy.
Our advertising agencies may also use web beacons and cookies to track your activity on our website
originating from the advertisement. However, we will not provide your personal information to our
advertising agencies. Our advertising agencies maintain their own privacy policies, and you should also
review those.
Links to non-Rackspace Websites
We may provide links to third-party Websites for you convenience and information. The privacy practices
of those sites may differ from Rackspace practices and are not controlled by Rackspace and covered by this
Privacy Statement. We do not make any representations about third-party Websites. We encourage you
to review their Privacy Policies before submitting your personal data.
Sensitive Information
We will not intentionally collect or maintain, and do not want you to provide, any information regarding
your medical or health condition, race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs
or other sensitive information.
                                                                                                  Rackspace Ltd
                                                                   4 The Square, Stockley Park, Uxbridge UB11 1ET
                                                            Tel: +44 (0) 20 8734 2500 Fax: +44 (0) 20 8606 6107
                                                                                          Web: www.rackspace.co.uk

UK Privacy Policy
V: 100118
Children’s Online Privacy Protection
Our services are not designed for or directed to children under the age of 18, and we will not intentionally
collect or maintain information about anyone under the age of 18.
     2. WHAT DO WE USE THIS INFORMATION FOR?
Personal Information
We may use personal information to process service requests, handle orders, deliver products and services,
process payments, communicate with you about orders provide access to secure areas of the website,
recommend merchandise and services that might be of interest to you, to personalise your visit to our
website, and to enable us to review, develop and continually improve the products services and offers we
provide online. We also use this information to prevent or detect fraud or abuses of our website and to
enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions on our behalf.
Contact Information
We use visitor information to send information about our company to visitors and to get in touch with
them when necessary. We also use the information we collect to improve the content of our websites and
as training aides for our employees. Visitors are given the choice at the point when we request their
information.
Financial Information and payment card details
We may ask visitors to enter credit card or account information in order to process orders for services
placed with Rackspace. Financial information provided via our website or via the MyRackspace portal is
encrypted for its protection prior to its transmission over the internet. We collect this information on a
transaction-by-transaction basis and will not authorise the release of the information with anyone not
directly involved in processing the transaction. This information may be encrypted and stored for logging
purposes in accordance with applicable regulatory requirements.
Credit card numbers are used only for processing payments and are not used for any other purposes.
When we use third party service providers for credit card processing services we will enter into a written
agreement with such third party ensuring appropriate security and confidentiality measures are in place in
safeguarding your personal data.
We use web visit information to measure interest in and develop our web pages and marketing plans,
customize the content you view on your web visits based on your activity on past visits, and administer our
website.
         We use the visitors’ IP address to help diagnose problems with our servers, and to administer our
         websites.
         We use cookies to help us recognise visitors as unique visitors (just a number) when they return to
         our websites For example, if there are 1,000 visits to our website on a certain day, we can use
         cookies to discover how many of those visits were made via the same browser (same visitor). We
                                                                                                  Rackspace Ltd
                                                                     4 The Square, Stockley Park, Uxbridge UB11 1ET
                                                              Tel: +44 (0) 20 8734 2500 Fax: +44 (0) 20 8606 6107
                                                                                          Web: www.rackspace.co.uk

UK Privacy Policy
V: 100118
         may also use the cookie to discover whether a certain visitor has visited our site more than once,
         and the source for each visit. We also use cookies to: allow us to tailor content or advertisements
         to match your preferred interest; avoid showing visitors the same advertisements repeatedly;
         compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how users use our site and
         to help us improve the structure of our Website (we cannot identify visitors personally in this way);
         count the number of anonymous users of our sites.
         We use web beacons to count the number of times that our advertisements and web-based email
    content are viewed. We combine web beacon information with cookies to track activity on our website
    originating from advertisements and web-based email content.
We use information you provide to us via chat, email, web forms and other communications to
correspond with you about services you may be interested in purchasing. If you elect to purchase a service
online using a web form, we will use the information to establish your account. Information you submit in
writing, such as chat, email, and web form information is archived and may be tied to information that we
collect about your web visits. Unless you are expressly advised that a telephone call is being recorded, we
do not record telephone conversations, but we may enter information you provide via telephone into our
systems to use for the purposes described in this paragraph.
     3. DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
Disclosure to Third Parties
Personal information we gather is for internal use only and will not authorise the release of this information
to anyone outside Rackspace (save for third party service providers to Rackspace who perform functions on
our behalf but in such event personal information will only be shared to the extent reasonably necessary to
perform their functions and they will not be authorized to use it for any other function), unless you have
consented to such disclosure.
Should you breach our terms and conditions or website terms, or if we are under a duty to disclose or share
your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, we may disclose your information to a
relevant authority. This may include exchanging information with other companies and organisations for
the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction. In particular, we may release the information
we collect to third parties when we believe it is appropriate to comply with the law, to enforce our legal
rights, to protect the rights and safety of others, or to assist with industry efforts to control fraud, spam or
other undesirable conduct.
We may release the information we collect to third parties, where the information is provided to enable
such third party to provide services to us, provided that the third party has agreed to use at least the same
level of privacy protections described in this Privacy Policy, and is permitted to use the information only for
the purpose of providing services to us.
                                                                                                     Rackspace Ltd
                                                                     4 The Square, Stockley Park, Uxbridge UB11 1ET
                                                             Tel: +44 (0) 20 8734 2500 Fax: +44 (0) 20 8606 6107
                                                                                            Web: www.rackspace.co.uk

UK Privacy Policy
V: 100118
If we ever sell our business, your web visit and other information will likely be included with the transferred
assets.
If we wish to give your contact or personal information to a third party under any other circumstances, we
will notify you and give you a chance to opt out.
Disclosure to Rackspace Affiliates in the US
Please note that your information regarding service requests, service orders, handling orders, delivering
services and processing payments may be stored and processed on computer systems of our US affiliate,
Rackspace US, Inc. Rackspace US, Inc. has certified to the United States Department of Commerce that it
complies with the Safe Harbor framework as to that personal data designated in the Safe Harbor
certificate. The Safe Harbor certificate can be found at https://www.export.gov/safehrbr/list.aspx.
Any disclosure of personal information will be strictly controlled and made fully in accordance with current
UK legislation, in particular the UK Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act).
     4. OPTING OUT OF COMMUNICATION
You may withdraw your consent to our use of your personal information, including your opting out of
receiving future marketing mailings, at any time by emailing us at an ‘unsubscribe’ e-mail
unsubscribe@rackspace.co.uk. For other ways to contact us please see our Contact Us page. We will
return or destroy your personal information within 5 days of receipt of your withdrawal of consent.
     5. HOW SECURE IS THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT?
Rackspace is committed to industry best practices approaches concerning security measures to prevent the
loss, misuse and alteration of the information in our possession. We use various security measures to
protect the information we collect, as appropriate to the type of information, including encryption,
firewalls, and access controls. Visitor textual information is encrypted during transmission, our company
databases are accessible only by persons who have entered into and are bound by a confidentiality and
nondisclosure agreement with Rackspace.
     6. RIGHT TO ACCESS YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
The Data Protection Act 1998 gives you the right to access information held about you. You can obtain
access to your personal information held by us by putting your request in writing and sending a cheque for
£10 (to cover administration costs for collating this information), made payable to Rackspace Ltd 4 The
Square, Stockley Park, Uxbridge UB11 1ET. If you have any questions about Rackspace’s Data Protection
Policy please write to our Data Protection Officer or e-mail us at dataprivacy@rackspace.co.uk.
We always endeavour to make sure that the information we hold about you is accurate and up to date, if
you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to us or e-
                                                                                                   Rackspace Ltd
                                                                    4 The Square, Stockley Park, Uxbridge UB11 1ET
                                                            Tel: +44 (0) 20 8734 2500 Fax: +44 (0) 20 8606 6107
                                                                                           Web: www.rackspace.co.uk

UK Privacy Policy
V: 100118
mail us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be
incorrect.
     7. CHANGES
Our business changes constantly and our UK Privacy Policy may also change from time to time. You should
check our website frequently to see recent changes, however, we will never materially change our policies
and practices to make them less protective of personal information collected in the past without your prior
consent. Unless stated otherwise, our current UK Privacy Policy applies to all information that we have
about you. This Privacy Policy was last updated on 15 January 2010.
                                                                                                 Rackspace Ltd
                                                                 4 The Square, Stockley Park, Uxbridge UB11 1ET
                                                          Tel: +44 (0) 20 8734 2500 Fax: +44 (0) 20 8606 6107
                                                                                         Web: www.rackspace.co.uk
